Mrunal Shrikant Gaurkar Software Developer

+91-7264066280 gaurkarmrunal27@gmail.com Nagpur, Maharashtra

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrunal-gaurkar-7698m1967p https://github.com/mrunal200698

https://mrunal200698.github.io/Mrunal-Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Full Stack Software Professional with a strong background in Insurance and e-commerce domain, possessing **2.3 years of expertise** in developing end to end applications using various tech stacks like Java, J2EE, Spring Boot, Microservices, etc. Experienced in version control with GIT and CI/CD tools like Jenkins. Specialized in backend application development, I have consistently demonstrated a strong passion for continuous learning and expanding my skill set.

SKILLS

Programming Languages	Java (8 & above versions), J2EE, JDBC, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Security,
	JSP, Servlets
Frameworks	Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Microservices, REST API, JavaScript
Programming Concepts	OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms, Collection
Database	MySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server
Scripting Languages	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React JS, Node JS, jQuery, Ajax, XML, JSON
	Agile Methodology, SDLC, Debugging
DevOps Tools	Git, Jenkins, Junit, Docker, Jira, Maven
IDEs	STS, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ Idea, Postman
OS Platform	Windows, Linux
Application Servers	Apache Tomcat
Office Packages	MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint
Soft Skills	Problem-solving, Communication (verbal & written), Analytical and Logical
	Thinking skills, Team Player, Self-Starter, Attentive to details, Interpersonal Skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sapiens Technologies India Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru, Karnataka Associate Software Developer (June 2022- Dec 2023)

- **Implemented** over 6 user stories, **enhancing** code efficiency by 18%, and **reducing** defects by 75% through meticulous root cause analysis, unit testing, and debugging.
- **Engineered** approx. 3 complex backend functionalities to streamline approval and cancellation processes for bank payment requests in reinsurance, **boosting** operational efficiency and **reducing** processing time by 25%.
- **Integrated** RESTful APIs to streamline data flow and enhance application functionality, **resolving** critical bugs with optimized solutions.
- **Automated** CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins, **increasing** build efficiency by 30%.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure seamless integration of new technologies and solutions.
- **Involved** in application development, Unit Testing, build Deployment using **Jar deployment** and delivery process. Following best practices like **Agile methodology.**
- Utilized Tech Stack—Java, J2EE (Servlet, JSP), Spring Batch, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Hibernate, EJB, MySQL, JDBC, Junit, Maven, Eclipse.

Nimbja Security Solutions Pvt Ltd, Pune, Maharashtra

(Nov 2020- Aug 2021)

Jr. Software Engineer

- **Developed** and maintained scalable applications using **Java**, **improving** application performance, reliability, and efficiency by 25% through effective **bug fixes**.
- **Utilized** Agile Development methodology and tools such as JIRA to ensure timely and high-quality delivery of projects.
- Involved in application development using Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Microservices.
- Enhanced user experience and application functionality by designing responsive and user-friendly interfaces with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript React JS.

PROJECTS

Reinsurance (Sapiens Technologies)

(July 2022- Dec 2023)

• Involved in application development, Unit Testing, build Deployment using Jar deployment and delivery process. Following best practices like Agile methodology. Utilized Tech Stack—Java, J2EE (Servlet, JSP), Spring Batch, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Hibernate, EJB, MySQL, JDBC, Junit, Maven, Eclipse.

Tourist-Inn Booking System (CDAC)

(Feb 2022- April 2022)

• **Built** a real-time booking application for budget-friendly guestroom reservations, utilizing the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) and **designed** a responsive UI with React and Bootstrap.

Jukebox (CDAC) (Dec 2021- Feb 2022)

• **Designed** a console-based Jukebox application for creating and managing playlists, integrating features like adding, deleting, updating, and shuffling songs, and **implemented** it using Data Structures and MySQL.

Other

• **Developed** an e-commerce gifting website using basic web development technologies, **currently working on** a Spring Boot Microservices Project with OAuth authorization and JWT of Spring Security Framework.

EDUCATION

2021-2022 Center for Development in Advanced Computing (CDAC)Diploma in Advanced Computing (PGDAC)

Pune, Maharashtra

2016-2020 Rajiv Gandhi College of Engineering and Research
Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering)
Passed out Year: 2020 CGPA: 8.19

Nagpur, Maharashtra

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified in PG Diploma in Advanced Computing from CDAC with Grade A
- Published paper in International Journal of Engineering and Creative Science (IJECS), eISSN: 2581-6667, Volume: 03 Issue: 02| Feb-2020.
- Published paper in International Journal for Research in Applied Science & Engineering Technology (IJRASET), ISSN: 2321-9653, Volume: 08 Issue: 02| Feb-2020.